<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsuru Adepeju&#39;s Homepage on Monsuru Adepeju&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monsuru Adepeju&#39;s Homepage on Monsuru Adepeju&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar Series - 2nd October 2018</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monsuru Adepeju, Samuel Langton, and Jon Bannister&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the 1990s, a dramatic decline in recorded crime has been observed across many developed polities (Aebi and Linde, 2010; Tseloni et al., 2010). Set against this finding, there has been limited attention paid the crime drop at the neighbourhood level, an exception being Bannister et al (2017) who found marked distinction in the crime drop trajectories of different neighbourhood groupings in Glasgow. Building upon this finding, this paper seeks to explore whether the crime drop has resulted in an increase in inequalities in the exposure to crime. The analysis utilises police recorded property and violent crime in Glasgow and Birmingham, enabling assessment of whether any observed shifting inequalities in the exposure to crime can be considered place specific or part of wider area trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This research deploys a novel &amp;lsquo;inequity&amp;rsquo; kmeans clustering (iClustering) technique (Adepeju, Langton and Bannister, in preparation) to examine the longitudinal crime trajectories of neighbourhoods. This technique offers substantive advantage over existing longitudinal clustering techniques (Curman et al., 2015; Weisburd et al., 2004; Wheeler et al., 2015) enabling clearer delineation of neighbourhood crime trajectories. The results indicate growing inequalities in the exposure to crime and may be applied, in an era of fiscal austerity, to help target and prioritise policing interventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;delivered-by&#34;&gt;Delivered by:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Monsuru Adepeju&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar Series | 13th November 2018</title>
      <link>/seminars/tutor_eg_131118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/seminars/tutor_eg_131118/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#To be announced soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar Series | 2nd October, 2018</title>
      <link>/seminars/tutor_eg_021018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/seminars/tutor_eg_021018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The crime drop and neighbourhood inequalities in the exposure to crime: A longitudinal study of violent and property crime in England (2001-2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the 1990s, a dramatic decline in recorded crime has been observed across many developed polities (Aebi and Linde, 2010; Tseloni et al., 2010). Set against this finding, there has been limited attention paid the crime drop at the neighbourhood level, an exception being Bannister et al (2017) who found marked distinction in the crime drop trajectories of different neighbourhood groupings in Glasgow. Building upon this finding, this paper seeks to explore whether the crime drop has resulted in an increase in inequalities in the exposure to crime. The analysis utilises police recorded property and violent crime in Glasgow and Birmingham, enabling assessment of whether any observed shifting inequalities in the exposure to crime can be considered place specific or part of wider area trends.
This research deploys a novel &lt;code&gt;inequity&lt;/code&gt; kmeans clustering (iClustering) technique (Adepeju, Langton and Bannister, in preparation) to examine the longitudinal crime trajectories of neighbourhoods. This technique offers substantive advantage over existing longitudinal clustering techniques (Curman et al., 2015; Weisburd et al., 2004; Wheeler et al., 2015) enabling clearer delineation of neighbourhood crime trajectories. The results indicate growing inequalities in the exposure to crime and may be applied, in an era of fiscal austerity, to help target and prioritise policing interventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Monsuru Adepeju&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar Series | 30th October 2018</title>
      <link>/seminars/tutor_eg_301018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/seminars/tutor_eg_301018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Using Agent-Based Simulation for socio-ecological uncertainty analysis&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both social and ecological systems can be highly complex, but the interaction between these two worlds - a socio-ecological system (SES) - can add even greater levels. However, the maintenance of SES are vital to our well-being and the health of the planet. We do not know how such systems work in practice and we lack good data about them (especially the ecological side) so predicting the effect of any particular policy is infeasible. Here we present an approach which tries to understand some of the ways in which SES may go wrong, but constructing different complex simulation models and analysing the emergent outcomes. These, in silico, examples can allow for the institution of targeted data gathering instruments that give the earliest possible warning of deleterious outcomes, and thus allow for timely remedial responses. An example of this approach applied to fisheries is described.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;author&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bruce Edmonds&lt;/strong&gt; is Professor of Social Simulation and Director of the Centre for Policy Modelling (CfPM). The CfPM was formed in 1992 as one of the first research centres in the complexity sciences in the UK. It applies computer science techniques to understand issues in the social world. Since 1992 it has developed to be one of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading research centres in agent-based modelling. For more about the Centre see &lt;a href=&#34;http://cfpm.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://cfpm.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delivered-by&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delivered by:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Edmonds (Prof.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar series | 16th October 2018</title>
      <link>/seminars/tutor_eg_161018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/seminars/tutor_eg_161018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hidden inequality in the exposure to crime? Unreported, reported and recorded crime in Greater Manchester 2012-2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The level of recorded crime varies markedly across Greater Manchester, with deprived communities bearing a disproportionate burden. However, does recorded crime accurately capture inequality in the exposure to crime? Recorded crime is composed of reported incidents that are evidenced by the police to be a crime. If reporting and evidencing are consistent across communities and crime types, then recorded crime can be argued to be reflective of the lived reality. In other words, whilst some crimes remain hidden, their proportionate distribution falls in line with recorded crime. But, if reporting and evidencing varies across communities and by crime type, recorded crime can be argued to be unreflective of the lived reality, to mask hidden inequality in the exposure to crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper we probe the existence of hidden inequality in the exposure to violent, property and nuisance crimes across communities in Greater Manchester, classified according to their level of deprivation, between 2012 and 2016. To do so, we utilise data from the Crime Survey of England and Wales, reported (incident) and recorded crime data, as well as census data. The research deploys a Bayesian hierarchical space-time model using Integrated Nested Laplace Approximation (INLA) to examine the relationships between unreported, reported and recorded crime types across communities and through time. The results demonstrate the existence of marked hidden inequality in the exposure to crime, though this varies substantively by crime type. Finally, we discuss the implications of the findings for the advance of effective, efficient and legitimate policing interventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Stephanie Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; is a Lecturer in Criminology and Quantitative Methods at Manchester Metropolitan University, and an associate member of the Manchester Metropolitan Crime and Well-Being Big Data Centre. Stephanie obtained her PhD in Applied Social Statistics from Lancaster University, where her research focused on developing methods to measure sentence severity, and applying these methods to assess sentencing disparity in England and Wales. Her research continues to employ a range of quantitative techniques and methods to investigate disproportionality within the criminal justice system, particularly in relation to the spatial and temporal interplay with inequality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Karolina Krzemieniewska-Nandwani&lt;/strong&gt; is a Research Associate at the Manchester Metropolitan University Crime and Well-Being Big Data Centre. She specialises in data analysis and statistics, with particular interest in classification techniques and time series analysis. Her industrial background has equipped her with practical experience in the application of advanced statistical methods suitable for analysis of crime, policing and health data. Her most recent projects involve the analysis of crime harm and police resource demand modelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delivered-by&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delivered by:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karolina Krzemieniewska-Nandwani (Dr.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delineators: Geographical Space</title>
      <link>/project/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section describes a set of analytical tools for delineating a geographical space. A &lt;code&gt;geographical space&lt;/code&gt; refers to a large geographical area, such as a town or a  city, subdivided into a set of smaller administrative or non-administrative units.  An example of an administrative unit is a district, neighbourhood, county or ward demarcation, while an example of a non-administrative unit is a system of regular grid or street network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spatial analysis, it is often required to &lt;strong&gt;modify&lt;/strong&gt; (as in the example of an administrative unit) or &lt;strong&gt;create&lt;/strong&gt; (as in the example of a non-administrative unit) some of these units, based on a given geographical specification. The following subsection will introduce two tools and how to download them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-spatial-grid-creator&#34;&gt;1. Spatial grid creator:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool creates a regular grid system over a geographical space. The tool requires a user to supply a spatial boundary of an area (in Esri format - .shp) and specify the grid size. The tool detects the spatial extent of the boundary and automatically create a system of regular grids, of the size specified, over the area. Below are examples regular grid systems of varying sizes, created by this tool, over the City of Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insert figs. here:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applications&lt;/strong&gt;
The use of arbitrary grid system is common in crime analytics for some special reasons, which include confidentiality protection and as alternative in absence of a reasonably small adminstrative units. In particular, the grid systems have been used in hotspot policing in order to enable a more focussed targetting of problematic areas (Mohler et al. 2011).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool can be downloaded directly from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MAnalytics/Creating-a-spatial-grid-system-over-an-area&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/MAnalytics/Creating-a-spatial-grid-system-over-an-area&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-bdc-geoconverter&#34;&gt;2. BDC_GeoConverter:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool is developed to complement an online tool called &lt;code&gt;Geoconverter&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://geoconvert.mimas.ac.uk/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://geoconvert.mimas.ac.uk/index.html&lt;/a&gt;). The Geoconverter is used for matching changed geographical units in the UK, or apportioning a dataset from an original geographical demarcation to a modified/changed geographical demarcation. For example, during 2011 census in the UK, it can be observed that some of the census units, namely LSOAs and OAs, have been modified (either merged or split) when compared to their corresponding 2001 census units. In Birmingham city for example, 10%* of 2011 LSOA units have been affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a longitudinal analysis as an example, the aforementioned changes is &lt;code&gt;problematic&lt;/code&gt;. In an effort to address this, the Geoconverter tool is created, and to apportion any data from 2001 unit demarcation to 2011 unit demarcation, and vice versa. Alternatively, the tool can be used to generate a &lt;code&gt;look-up table&lt;/code&gt; that provide a summary of those changes for the entire UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The look-up table is particularly useful for anyone who might want to carry out the apportioning tasks programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the &lt;code&gt;BDC_Geoconverter&lt;/code&gt; is created to deal with two problems that are not addressed by the online Geoconverter. First, the online Geoconverter fails to capture some OAs that exist in 2001 and still exist in 2011, but have now been renamed. This is scenario is most common in Greater Glasgow where high-rise building were demolished and re-built as smaller building units, and therefore renamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that the work of BDC_Geoconverter still depends largely on the look-up table generated from the online Geoconverter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool can be downloaded directly from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MAnalytics/BDC-Geoconverter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/MAnalytics/BDC-Geoconverter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictors: Geographical Processes</title>
      <link>/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In geographical point data analysis, spatial aggregation boundary delineations&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulators: Space-time Point Patterns</title>
      <link>/project/internal-project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/internal-project2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Person Re-Identification System For Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication_/person-re-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication_/person-re-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Society of Criminology - 29th August 2018</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;title&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Title:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offender residential concentration: a longitudinal study in the United Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;authors&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Authors:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samuel Langton &amp;amp; Monsuru Adepeju&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;abstract&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Abstract:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study examines..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can embed an R code chunk like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;summary(cars)
##      speed           dist       
##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  
##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  
##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  
##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  
##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  
##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00
fit &amp;lt;- lm(dist ~ speed, data = cars)
fit
## 
## Call:
## lm(formula = dist ~ speed, data = cars)
## 
## Coefficients:
## (Intercept)        speed  
##     -17.579        3.932&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also embed plots. See Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:pie&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1))
pie(
  c(280, 60, 20),
  c(&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;),
  col = c(&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;),
  init.angle = -50, border = NA
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:pie&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown_files/figure-html/pie-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A fancy pie chart.&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: A fancy pie chart.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile visual clothing search</title>
      <link>/publication_/clothing-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication_/clothing-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/example-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/example-slides/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
