<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsuru Adepeju&#39;s Homepage on Monsuru Adepeju&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>https://mnalytics.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monsuru Adepeju&#39;s Homepage on Monsuru Adepeju&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar Series - 2nd October 2018</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monsuru Adepeju, Samuel Langton, and Jon Bannister&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the 1990s, a dramatic decline in recorded crime has been observed across many developed polities (Aebi and Linde, &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10610-010-9130-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;; Tseloni et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1477370810367014&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;). Set against this finding, there has been limited attention paid the crime drop at the neighbourhood level, an exception being Bannister et al (&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bjc/article/58/1/177/3102956&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;) who found marked distinction in the crime drop trajectories of different neighbourhood groupings in Glasgow. Building upon this finding, this paper seeks to explore whether the crime drop has resulted in an increase in inequalities in the exposure to crime. The analysis utilises police recorded property and violent crime in Glasgow and Birmingham, enabling assessment of whether any observed shifting inequalities in the exposure to crime can be considered place specific or part of wider area trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This research deploys a novel &lt;em&gt;inequity&lt;/em&gt; kmeans clustering (&lt;em&gt;iClustering&lt;/em&gt;) technique (Adepeju, Langton and Bannister, &lt;em&gt;in preparation&lt;/em&gt;) to examine the longitudinal crime trajectories of neighbourhoods. This technique offers substantive advantage over existing longitudinal clustering techniques (Curman et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10940-014-9228-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;; Weisburd et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1745-9125.2004.tb00521.x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/a&gt;; Wheeler et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10940-015-9268-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;) enabling clearer delineation of neighbourhood crime trajectories. The results indicate growing inequalities in the exposure to crime and may be applied, in an era of fiscal austerity, to help target and prioritise policing interventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;delivered-by&#34;&gt;Delivered by:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Monsuru Adepeju&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar Series | 13th November 2018</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/seminars/tutor_eg_131118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/seminars/tutor_eg_131118/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Offender residential concentrations: a longitudinal study in the United Kingdom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having common roots in crime concentration research, little attention has been paid to the geographic distribution of offender residences. Questions remain unanswered about how stable offender residential concentrations are over time, or how sensitive this stability is to the choice of spatial scale. Given that many offenders commit crime close to where they reside, an important piece of the puzzle may be missing in our efforts to understand the longitudinal concentration of crime. This paper addresses these shortcomings using 10 years of geocoded offender residence data from Birmingham, England. Descriptive and multilevel analyses are used to establish the most appropriate unit of analysis. Non-parametric longitudinal clustering methods are then deployed to disentangle local variance in concentrations. Individual-level population flows are visualised to demonstrate how even small-area analysis can hide more complex underlying processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;author&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sam Langton&lt;/strong&gt; is a PhD candidate at Manchester Metropolitan Crime and Well-Being Big Data Centre. His research focuses on the geographic distribution of offender residences in Birmingham, England. Sam is supervised by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.mmu.ac.uk/sociology/staff/profile/?id=130&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jon Bannister&lt;/a&gt; (Sociology), &lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.mmu.ac.uk/sociology/staff/profile/?id=128&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gary Pollock&lt;/a&gt; (Sociology) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.mmu.ac.uk/scmdt/staff/profile/index.php?id=2378&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Liangxiu Han&lt;/a&gt; (Computing). He obtained a BSc in Social Policy and Government from the London School of Economics (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lse.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LSE&lt;/a&gt;). After working in accounting for two years, he moved to the Netherlands to complete a two-year MSc in Sociology and Social Research at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uu.nl/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Utrecht University&lt;/a&gt;. Whilst there, he worked as an intern at the Netherlands Institute for the Study of Crime and Law Enforcement (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nscr.nl/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NSCR&lt;/a&gt;) in Amsterdam, where he completed his master&amp;rsquo;s dissertation with Utrecht University on residential burglary target selection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar Series | 2nd October, 2018</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/seminars/tutor_eg_021018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/seminars/tutor_eg_021018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The crime drop and neighbourhood inequalities in the exposure to crime: A longitudinal study of violent and property crime in England (2001-2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the 1990s, a dramatic decline in recorded crime has been observed across many developed polities (Aebi and Linde, &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10610-010-9130-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;; Tseloni et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1477370810367014&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;). Set against this finding, there has been limited attention paid the crime drop at the neighbourhood level, an exception being Bannister et al (&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/bjc/article/58/1/177/3102956&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;) who found marked distinction in the crime drop trajectories of different neighbourhood groupings in Glasgow. Building upon this finding, this paper seeks to explore whether the crime drop has resulted in an increase in inequalities in the exposure to crime. The analysis utilises police recorded property and violent crime in Glasgow and Birmingham, enabling assessment of whether any observed shifting inequalities in the exposure to crime can be considered place specific or part of wider area trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This research deploys a novel &lt;em&gt;inequity&lt;/em&gt; kmeans clustering (&lt;em&gt;iClustering&lt;/em&gt;) technique (Adepeju, Langton and Bannister, &lt;em&gt;in preparation&lt;/em&gt;) to examine the longitudinal crime trajectories of neighbourhoods. This technique offers substantive advantage over existing longitudinal clustering techniques (Curman et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10940-014-9228-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;; Weisburd et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1745-9125.2004.tb00521.x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/a&gt;; Wheeler et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10940-015-9268-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;) enabling clearer delineation of neighbourhood crime trajectories. The results indicate growing inequalities in the exposure to crime and may be applied, in an era of fiscal austerity, to help target and prioritise policing interventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Monsuru Adepeju&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar Series | 30th October 2018</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/seminars/tutor_eg_301018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/seminars/tutor_eg_301018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Using Agent-Based Simulation for socio-ecological uncertainty analysis&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both social and ecological systems can be highly complex, but the interaction between these two worlds - a &lt;em&gt;socio-ecological system (SES)&lt;/em&gt; - can add even greater levels. However, the maintenance of SES are vital to our well-being and the health of the planet. We do not know how such systems work in practice and we lack good data about them (especially the ecological side) so predicting the effect of any particular policy is infeasible. Here we present an approach which tries to understand some of the ways in which SES may go wrong, but constructing different complex simulation models and analysing the emergent outcomes. These, in silico, examples can allow for the institution of targeted data gathering instruments that give the earliest possible warning of deleterious outcomes, and thus allow for timely remedial responses. An example of this approach applied to fisheries is described.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;author&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bruce Edmonds&lt;/strong&gt; is Professor of Social Simulation and Director of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cfpm.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Centre for Policy Modelling (CfPM)&lt;/a&gt;. The CfPM was formed in 1992 as one of the first research centres in the complexity sciences in the UK. It applies computer science techniques to understand issues in the social world. Since 1992 it has developed to be one of the world&amp;rsquo;s leading research centres in agent-based modelling. For more about the Centre see &lt;a href=&#34;http://cfpm.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://cfpm.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delivered-by&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delivered by:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruce Edmonds (Prof.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDC Seminar series | 16th October 2018</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/seminars/tutor_eg_161018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/seminars/tutor_eg_161018/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hidden inequality in the exposure to crime? Unreported, reported and recorded crime in Greater Manchester 2012-2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The level of recorded crime varies markedly across Greater Manchester, with deprived communities bearing a disproportionate burden. However, does recorded crime accurately capture inequality in the exposure to crime? Recorded crime is composed of reported incidents that are evidenced by the police to be a crime. If reporting and evidencing are consistent across communities and crime types, then recorded crime can be argued to be reflective of the lived reality. In other words, whilst some crimes remain hidden, their proportionate distribution falls in line with recorded crime. But, if reporting and evidencing varies across communities and by crime type, recorded crime can be argued to be unreflective of the lived reality, to mask hidden inequality in the exposure to crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper we probe the existence of hidden inequality in the exposure to violent, property and nuisance crimes across communities in Greater Manchester, classified according to their level of deprivation, between 2012 and 2016. To do so, we utilise data from the Crime Survey of England and Wales, reported (incident) and recorded crime data, as well as census data. The research deploys a Bayesian hierarchical space-time model using Integrated Nested Laplace Approximation (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.r-inla.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;INLA&lt;/a&gt;) to examine the relationships between unreported, reported and recorded crime types across communities and through time. The results demonstrate the existence of marked hidden inequality in the exposure to crime, though this varies substantively by crime type. Finally, we discuss the implications of the findings for the advance of effective, efficient and legitimate policing interventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;authors&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Stephanie Wallace&lt;/strong&gt; is a Lecturer in Criminology and Quantitative Methods at Manchester Metropolitan University, and an associate member of the Manchester Metropolitan Crime and Well-Being Big Data Centre. Stephanie obtained her PhD in Applied Social Statistics from Lancaster University, where her research focused on developing methods to measure sentence severity, and applying these methods to assess sentencing disparity in England and Wales. Her research continues to employ a range of quantitative techniques and methods to investigate disproportionality within the criminal justice system, particularly in relation to the spatial and temporal interplay with inequality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Karolina Krzemieniewska-Nandwani&lt;/strong&gt; is a Research Associate at the Manchester Metropolitan University Crime and Well-Being Big Data Centre. She specialises in data analysis and statistics, with particular interest in classification techniques and time series analysis. Her industrial background has equipped her with practical experience in the application of advanced statistical methods suitable for analysis of crime, policing and health data. Her most recent projects involve the analysis of crime harm and police resource demand modelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delivered-by&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delivered by:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karolina Krzemieniewska-Nandwani (Dr.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delineators: Geographical Space</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/project/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/project/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section describes a set of analytical tools for delineating a geographical space. A &lt;em&gt;geographical space&lt;/em&gt; refers to a large geographical area, such as a town or a  city, subdivided into a set of smaller administrative or non-administrative units.  An example of an administrative unit is a district, neighbourhood, county or ward demarcation, while an example of a non-administrative unit is a system of regular grid or street network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spatial analysis, it is often required to &lt;strong&gt;modify&lt;/strong&gt; an existing geographical delineation or &lt;strong&gt;create&lt;/strong&gt; a new one, based on a given specification. The following subsection will talk about two tools, one for creating a new geographical delineation (demarcation), and the other for modifying an existing geographical delineation. The link to download the tools are also provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-spatial-grid-generator&#34;&gt;1. Spatial grid generator:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool creates a regular grid system over a geographical space. The tool requires a user to supply a spatial boundary of an area (in Esri format - .shp) and specify the grid size. The tool detects the spatial extent of the boundary and automatically create a system of regular grids, of the size specified, over the area. Although, it is possible to create regular grids in the existing GIS software, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://desktop.arcgis.com/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ArcGIS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.qgis.org/en/site/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;QGIS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, however, the process in these software is not straightforward. Therefore, the key purpose of our &lt;em&gt;Spatial grid generator&lt;/em&gt; is to simplify this process. Below are examples regular grid systems of varying sizes, created by this tool, over the City of Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insert figs. here:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential Applications:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of arbitrary grid system is common in crime analytics for some special reasons, which include confidentiality protection and as alternative in absence of a reasonably small adminstrative units. In particular, the grid systems have been used in hotspot policing in order to enable a more focussed targetting of problematic areas (Mohler et al. 2011).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool can be &lt;strong&gt;downloaded&lt;/strong&gt; directly from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MAnalytics/Creating-a-spatial-grid-system-over-an-area&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-bdc-geoconverter&#34;&gt;2. BDC_GeoConverter:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool is developed to complement an online tool called &lt;a href=&#34;http://geoconvert.mimas.ac.uk/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Geoconverter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Geoconverter is used for matching changed geographical units, or apportioning a dataset from an original geographical demarcation to a modified/changed geographical demarcation. For example, during 2011 UK census, it is observed that some census units, namely LSOAs and OAs, have been modified (either merged or split) when compared to their corresponding 2001 units. In Birmingham city for example, 10%* of 2011 LSOA units were affected. In a longitudinal analysis as an example, the aforementioned changes is &lt;em&gt;problematic&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an effort to address this issue, the online Geoconverter tool is created, in order to apportion any data from 2001 census demarcation to 2011 census demarcation, or vice versa. Alternatively, the tool can be used to generate a &lt;em&gt;look-up table&lt;/em&gt; that provides the details those changes that have occured for the entire UK. For example, for any given 2001 unit code, the look-up table provides the corresponding (set of) 2011 unit codes and the share (ratio) of 2001 unit that each has got. The table will give &amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo; for any unit that remain the same in both years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The look-up table is particularly useful for anyone who might wish to carry out the apportioning task programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the &lt;em&gt;BDC_Geoconverter&lt;/em&gt; is created to deal with one key problem that is not addressed by the online Geoconverter. The online Geoconverter fails to capture some OAs that exist in 2001 and still exist in 2011, but have now been renamed (i.e. re-coded). This scenario is most common in Scotland area where high-rise buildings were demolished and re-built as smaller building units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt; that the work of BDC_Geoconverter still depends largely on the look-up table generated from the online Geoconverter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool was originally developed for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.mmu.ac.uk/crime-and-policing/big-data-centre/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Crime &amp;amp; Well_Being Big Data Centre&lt;/a&gt; and can be &lt;strong&gt;downloaded&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MAnalytics/BDC-Geoconverter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictors: Geographical Processes</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section introduces a set of predictive tools for certain geographical processes, such as crime and footfalls. The links to downloading these tools are also provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-grid-based-crime-hotspot-predictors&#34;&gt;1. Grid-based Crime Hotspot Predictors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crime Hotspot&lt;/em&gt; refers to an area with a high risk of crime. In practice, police are interested in crime hotspot in order to inform crime intervention. However, it requires the use of an analytical technique to identify hotspot areas and be able to rank them according to their level of severity. In a short-term crime intervention, the term &lt;em&gt;predictive hotspot&lt;/em&gt; has been coined to represent hotspot types where crimes are expected to occur in a very near future, such as within one or two days. A number of analytical tools have been developed in order to model this type of hotspot - these are the types provided here. In addition, we provide an idea of the relative accuracies of these techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;**Self-Exciting Point Process**

**Prospective Space-time Scan Statistics**

**Prospective Kernel Density Estiamtion Method**

**Prospective Hotspotting**
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-footfall-predictor&#34;&gt;2. Footfall Predictor&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool was developed as a part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://surf.leeds.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Surf Project&lt;/a&gt; funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://esrc.ukri.org/funding/funding-opportunities/future-research-leaders/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ESRC Future Research Leaders&lt;/a&gt; scheme. The tool, named as &lt;em&gt;Leeds Footfall Predictor&lt;/em&gt;, built on the work led by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickmalleson.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Nick Malleson&lt;/a&gt; which determined that the daily footfall rates observed in the Leeds city centre can be explained in terms of external variables, such as temperature, rainfall and holidays (See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nickmalleson/lcc-footfall/blob/master/LCC_Footfall.ipynb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). The research involved the application of different machine learning algorithms to a combination of these variables (predictors) and subsequently compared the accuracies of the former. It was established that the &lt;em&gt;Random Forest&lt;/em&gt; algorithm by &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1010933404324&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Breiman, 2001&lt;/a&gt; is the most accurate for forecasting footfall rates. Thus, the algorithm, as implemented in R by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-project.org/doc/Rnews/Rnews_2002-3.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Liaw and Wiener, 2002&lt;/a&gt;, was employed in the development of the Leeds Footfall Predictor. The tool was then deployed using the &lt;em&gt;RShinydashboard&lt;/em&gt; platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figures here (Developed by Monsuru Adepeju)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure above shows the homepage of the tool. For further details about &lt;a href=&#34;http://surf.leeds.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Surf Project&lt;/a&gt;, please contact &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickmalleson.co.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Nick Malleson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulators: Space-time Point Patterns</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/project/internal-project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/project/internal-project2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geographical processes such as crime, diseases, and pedestrian footfalls are extremely difficult to synthesise - they are inherently complex, and the theories for describing them are constantly evolving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers often find themselves in a very precarious situation when carrying out real-life research projects, where data required to complete such projects are unavailable. Evidently, there are a number of legitimate reasons why such data might not be available, including confidentiality issues and the lack availability of usable data formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the credit of some computer/geospatial scientists, certain successes have been achieved in the areas of geographical modelling through computer simulation approach. However, many of these simulations are often too tailored towards a single problem and may not be extensible to other related problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section, I introduce a &lt;em&gt;dynamic microsimulation framework&lt;/em&gt; for simulating &lt;em&gt;crime patterns&lt;/em&gt;. Patterns, arising from offenders routines activities have both spatial and temporal signatures of different types. Thus, this framework is aimed at allowing different combinations of these spatio-temporal signatures to be simulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This framework was originally described &lt;a href=&#34;http://eprints.whiterose.ac.uk/128602/1/monsuru_adepeju_gisruk2018.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-dynamic-microsimulation-framework-for-simulating-different-spatio-temporal-crime-patterns-dmfc&#34;&gt;A dynamic microsimulation framework for simulating different spatio-temporal crime patterns (DMfC).&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the field of animal ecology, &lt;em&gt;foraging animals&lt;/em&gt; are known to act cautiously in relation to the locations they prey - while in pursuit of food, they do not want to become foods for others.  In the field of criminology, this behavioural pattern has been likened to that of a human offender who carefully chooses his victims while, at the same time, avoiding being arrested. In constrast to criminology, a considerable progress has been made in modelling these foraging behaviours in animal ecology using computer simulation (Morales et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://esajournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1890/03-0269&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/a&gt;; McClintock et al., &lt;a href=&#34;https://esajournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1890/11-0326.1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;). This &lt;em&gt;DMfC&lt;/em&gt; builds on this progress and adapt the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/SiMRiv/SiMRiv.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;SimRiv&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; R-package (Quaglietta and Porto, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/SiMRiv/SiMRiv.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;) to synthesise a set of offenders and their potential victims within a hypothetical, constraint environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DMfC allows the user to specify the levels of spatial clustering and the type of temporal patterns to simulate. The interaction between spatial and temporal specifications results into a unique spatio-temporal pattern, which can be used for further crime studies. The &lt;em&gt;DMfC&lt;/em&gt; tool can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MAnalytics/DMfC/blob/master/DataSynthUsingR/SyntheticData_OptimalForaging.Rmd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Past invited talks</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;paper-presentations&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Paper presentations:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Langton, S. &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Adepeju, M.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;. A longitudinal study of offender residential concentration in the UK. Presented at the European Society of Criminology - Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina - 29th August 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adepeju, M.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt; Developing a hybrid hotspot approach for improving the accuracy of crime prediction. ECTQG 18th European Colloquium on Theoretical and Quantitative Geography, York, United Kingdom, September 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adepeju, M.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Cheng, T. &lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt; A Spatially-Integrated Sparse Point Time Series (SSPT) Prediction Method. The 26th Annual Conference of the International Environmetrics Society, Edinburgh, Scotland, UK July, 2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adepeju, M.&lt;/strong&gt;, Rosser, G., &amp;amp; Cheng T. &lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt; Comparative analysis of predictive hotspot methods. Association of American Geographers, Annual Meeting. Chicago, IL, USA, April 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adepeju, M.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Cheng, T. &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt; Prospective Space-Time Scan Statistics (STSS) for Crime Prediction. 22nd Annual Popfest conference, London, UK, August 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adepeju, M.&lt;/strong&gt;, Cheng, T., &amp;amp; Nakaya, T. &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt; Crime pattern detection for predictive policing. Association of American Geographers, Annual Meeting. Tampa, FL, USA, April 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheng, T. &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Adepeju, M.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt; Implications of the difference between the Prospective and Retrospective Space-time scan statistics. ECTQG 18th European Colloquium on Theoretical and Quantitative Geography, Dourdan, France, September 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://mnalytics.com/slides/example-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mnalytics.com/slides/example-slides/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
